https://compactinstruments.co.uk/privacy-policy-and-cookies/

Privacy Policy & Cookies
HomePrivacy Policy & Cookies
Privacy Policy & CookiesLee Crossey-Wilkinson2020-10-28T15:30:21+00:00
Privacy Policy & Cookies
What is this Privacy Policy for?
This privacy policy is for this website www.compactinstruments.co.uk and served by Compact Instruments Limited and governs the privacy of its users who choose to use it.
The policy sets out the different areas where user privacy is concerned and outlines the obligations & requirements of the users, the website and website owners. Furthermore the way this website processes, stores and protects user data and information will also be detailed within this policy.
The Website
This website and its owners take a proactive approach to user privacy and ensure the necessary steps are taken to protect the privacy of its users throughout their visiting experience. This website complies to all UK national laws and requirements for user privacy.
Use of Cookies
This website uses cookies to better the users experience while visiting the website. Where applicable this website uses a cookie control system allowing the user on their first visit to the website to allow or disallow the use of cookies on their computer / device. This complies with recent legislation requirements for websites to obtain explicit consent from users before leaving behind or reading files such as cookies on a user’s computer / device.
Cookies are small files saved to the user’s computers hard drive that track, save and store information about the user’s interactions and usage of the website. This allows the website, through its server to provide the users with a tailored experience within this website.
Users are advised that if they wish to deny the use and saving of cookies from this website on to their computers hard drive they should take necessary steps within their web browsers security settings to block all cookies from this website and its external serving vendors.
This website uses tracking software to monitor its visitors to better understand how they use it. This software is provided by Google Analytics which uses cookies to track visitor usage. The software will save a cookie to your computers hard drive in order to track and monitor your engagement and usage of the website, but will not store, save or collect personal information. You can read Google’s privacy policy here for further information www.google.com/policies/privacy
Other cookies may be stored to your computers hard drive by external vendors when this website uses referral programs, sponsored links or adverts. Such cookies are used for conversion and referral tracking and typically expire after 30 days, though some may take longer. No personal information is stored, saved or collected.
Contact & Communication
Users contacting this website and/or its owners do so at their own discretion and provide any such personal details requested at their own risk. Your personal information is kept private and stored securely until a time it is no longer required or has no use, as detailed in the Data Protection Act 1998. Every effort has been made to ensure a safe and secure form to email submission process but advise users using such form to email processes that they do so at their own risk.
This website and its owners use any information submitted to provide you with further information about the products / services they offer or to assist you in answering any questions or queries you may have submitted. This includes using your details to subscribe you to any email newsletter program the website operates but only if this was made clear to you and your express permission was granted when submitting any form to email process. Or whereby you the consumer have previously purchased from or enquired about purchasing from the company a product or service that the email newsletter relates to. This is by no means an entire list of your user rights in regard to receiving email marketing material. Your details are not passed on to any third parties.
External Links
Although this website only looks to include quality, safe and relevant external links, users are advised adopt a policy of caution before clicking any external web links mentioned throughout this website. (External links are clickable text / banner / image links to other websites, similar to; Folded Book Art or Cottages in Pembrokeshire.)
The owners of this website cannot guarantee or verify the contents of any externally linked website despite their best efforts. Users should therefore note they click on external links at their own risk and this website and its owners cannot be held liable for any damages or implications caused by visiting any external links mentioned.
Social Media Platforms
Communication, engagement and actions taken through external social media platforms that this website and its owners participate on are custom to the terms and conditions as well as the privacy policies held with each social media platform respectively.
Users are advised to use social media platforms wisely and communicate / engage upon them with due care and caution in regard to their own privacy and personal details. This website nor its owners will ever ask for personal or sensitive information through social media platforms and encourage users wishing to discuss sensitive details to contact them through primary communication channels such as by telephone or email.
This website may use social sharing buttons which help share web content directly from web pages to the social media platform in question. Users are advised before using such social sharing buttons that they do so at their own discretion and note that the social media platform may track and save your request to share a web page respectively through your social media platform account.
Resources & Further Information
Data Protection Act 1998
Privacy and Electronic Communications Regulations 2003
Privacy and Electronic Communications Regulations 2003 – The Guide
Twitter Privacy Policy
Facebook Privacy Policy
Google Privacy Policy
Cookie Policy
This website www.compactinstruments.co.uk (the “Site”) is owned and operated by Compact Instruments Limited.
Whenever you access our website, mobile site, or mobile applications on any device, information may be collected through the use of cookies and similar technologies.
By continuing to use the Site you agree to our use of cookies as described in this Cookies Policy.
What are cookies
List of cookies used on the Site
Managing cookies in your browser
Changes to our Cookie Policy
What are cookies?
Cookies are text files containing small amounts of information which are downloaded to your device when you visit a website. Cookies are then sent back to the originating website on each subsequent visit. Cookies are useful because they allow a website to recognise a user’s device. You can find more information about cookies at: www.allaboutcookies.org and www.youronlinechoices.eu
Cookies do lots of different jobs, like letting you navigate between pages efficiently, remembering your preferences, and generally improving the user experience. They can also help to ensure that adverts you see online are more relevant to you and your interests.
Cookies are referred to as session or persistent, depending on how long they are stored on your computer or device:
Session cookies only last for the length of your online session. They disappear from your computer or device when you close your browser.
Persistent cookies stay on your computer or device after the browser has been closed and last for a set period of time specified in the cookie. These cookies are activated each time you visit the site that generated the cookie.
List of cookies used on the Site
Name
Description
Information
__utma
Metrics: Google
compactinstruments.co.uk uses Google Analytics, a web analytics service provided by Google, Inc. Google Analytics sets a cookie in order to evaluate your use of the our website and compile reports on user activity. Google stores the information collected by the cookie on servers in the United States. Google may also transfer this information to third parties where required to do so by law, or where such third parties process the information on Google’s behalf. Google will not associate your IP address with any other data held by Google. By using compactinstruments.co.uk, you consent to the processing of data about you by Google in the manner and for the purposes set out above.
__utmb
Metrics: Google
__utmc
Metrics: Google
__utmz
Metrics: Google
Managing cookies in your browser
Modern browsers allow you to perform a number of tasks in relation to cookies including the ability to view the cookies currently stored on your computer or device and delete them on an individual basis, block third party cookies, block cookies from particular sites, prevent all cookies from being set and delete all cookies when you close your web browser.
You should note that any individual preferences will be lost if you delete cookies, including a preference to opt out of cookies (since this requires an opt-out cookie to be set). If you choose to block cookies completely, many websites will not work properly and some functionality may be lost.
The links below take you to the relevant ‘Help’ sections for the major web browsers. Here you will be able to find out more information about how to manage your cookies.
Internet Explorer: Manage & Customise Cookies
Firefox: Manage & Customise Cookies
Google Chrome: Manage & Customise Cookies
Opera: Manage & Customise Cookies
Safari: Manage & Customise Cookies
Safari iOS: Manage & Customise Cookies
Android: Manage & Customise Cookies
Blackberry: Manage & Customise Cookies
Windows Phone: Manage & Customise Cookies
Changes to our Cookies Policy
We may make changes to this cookies policy at any time. If we do this, we will post the changes on this page. Where appropriate, we may notify our customers and/or users of the change by email. You should, however, check this page from time to time to take notice of any changes.
Payment Methods
Useful Information
About Us
Calibration & Repairs
Christmas & New Year Delivery Period
Coronavirus (COVID-19)
Delivery Information
General Data Protection Regulation [GDPR]
Payment Methods
Privacy Policy & Cookies
Quality Policy
Terms & Conditions
Site Resources
ATEX – IECEx
BSI Membership
Instruction Manuals
Fax: +44 (0)1204 522285
Address: 61-65 Lever Street, Bolton,
Lancashire, BL3 2AB, United Kingdom
Facebook
Twitter
Compact Instruments Limited, 61-65 Lever Street, Bolton, Lancashire BL3 2AB Registered in England & Wales, Registered Number: 04795150Registered Office: 61-65 Lever Street, Bolton, Lancashire, BL3 2AB VAT Registration Number: GB 824 8697 84 © Copyright 2020. All Rights Reserved.
